A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Culture Program, Office Files of Linn F.C. Cary FA533
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Education and Culture Program, Office Files of Linn F.C. Cary
1962-1985
Rockefeller Archive Center
Cary, Linn F. C.
Ford Foundation
FA533
16.1 Cubic Feet 12 standard record storage boxes and 1 letter document box.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Arranged in 3 series:
1. Research Assistant to Frank Thomas.
2. Program Reviews.
3. Education and Culture Program.
Scope and Contents
Files span Cary's career at Ford and the variety of roles and activities.
Biographical / Historical
Linn F.C. Cary Mehta is a university literature lecturer who worked for several years at the Ford Foundation. She started as an Assistant to the President at the Ford Foundation and then moved into the U.S. and International Affairs Program, Education and Culture Program.
Cary's career as a university lecturer has included her positions at Columbia University and Vassar College. She started lecturing in Barnard College's English department in 2000.
Cary earned a B.A. in English and French literature from Yale University in 1977 and a M.A. in English language and literature from Oxford University in 1979. She earned a M.Phil and Ph.D. in comparative literature from Columbia University.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
- Research Assistant to Franklin Thomas Files, 1962-1983; I
  - Annual Report Essay/President's Review (with focus on nutrition), 1968-1981 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report Essay/President's Review, "Future Planning", 1962-1981 (Box 1)
  - Arts, Culture, and Education at the Ford Foundation -- Chronology and Programming History, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Biography -- Franklin Thomas, 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting -- Preliminary Recommendations, 1981 March (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting (June 1981) -- Minutes, Meeting Materials, Discussion Summaries, Budget Memoranda, Follow-up (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting (Sep 1981) -- Individual Committee Meeting Summaries, Notes, Memoranda (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting (Sep 1981) -- Docket, 1981 September 23-25 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting (Dec 1981) -- Schedule, Memoranda, Meeting Materials, etc., 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting (Mar 1982) -- Memoranda, Notes, Committee Meeting Summaries (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting (Jun 1982), incl. Human Rights and Governance Program Committee Materials -- Summaries, Notes, Reports, etc. (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting (Jun 1982) -- Project Redirection Meeting (re: pregnant teens and teen mothers), 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting (Dec 1982) -- Education and Culture Committee Meeting (12/8/82) -- Major Speaker Points, Notes, Board Meetings Schedule (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees Meetings (1981) -- Materials Prepared for Board Meetings under Franklin Thomas (Box 1)
  - Brower, Brock -- General File -- Christmas at the Ford Foundation, "Here at the Foundation" Report Re: Ford Foundation Programs, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Budget, Program, Grant Administration, Review and Approval Process, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Budget Review Meetings for FY 1982-1983 (and program support), 1981 (Box 1)
  - Budget Status Reports, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Consultants, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Conversations and Memoranda -- Staff Memoranda, Library Materials, etc., 1980 (Box 1)
  - Corporate Contributions, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Corporate Philanthropy, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Corporate Social Responsibility Reports (especially international), 1981 (Box 1)
  - Dressner, Howard -- Conversations, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Education and Public Policy -- Program Review (1980-1981) (Box 1)
  - "The Ford Foundation in Bangladesh" and Attached Memorandum, 1978 September (Box 1)
  - Foundations, 1980-1983 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation Publications, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
  - Ford Foundation Speeches, 1969-1983 (Box 2)
  - Grant Documents -- Instructions for Issuing/Approving Grants, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Grant Issuing Guidelines, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Growth Centres Project, 1971-1975 (Box 2)
  - Guildhall Speech and Report Re: Civil Rights Under Law Grant, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Health/Nutrition Programming, 1982 (Box 2)
  - History/Locations of Ford Foundation, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Information Manual for Information Resources Specialists, 1981 (Box 2)
  - International Division Program Reviews -- Population Program, circa 1980 (Box 2)
  - International Division Program Review, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC), 1981 (Box 2)
  - Management Budget Meetings -- International Division, Aug 12-14, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Management Budget Meetings -- DCP and U.S. Programs and International Relations Management Budget Meetings, 1981 July 9 (Box 2)
  - Management Budget Meetings -- Chairman/President/OGC/Secretary/Reports, Office of the Vice President and Comptroller, and Division of Financial Affairs Management Budget Meetings, 1981 July 13-17 (Box 2)
  - Management Budget Meetings -- Division of Organization and Management, 1981 July 15 (Box 2)
  - Management Costs, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Meetings -- Franklin Thomas/Outside, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Memoranda, Draft Papers Re: Program Planning, Budgets, Program Reviews, Index of Information Projects (1951-1981), 1979-1981 (Box 2)
  - Memoranda, Notes Re: Grants, Meetings, Papers, Travel, etc. (miscellaneous documents of Linn Cary as Research Assistant to Franklin Thomas), 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Moore/Houghton et al., 1980-1982 (Box 2)
  - National Affairs Program Review (1980-1981) Memorandum (Box 2)
  - Organization and Managment Outlines, Memoranda, etc., 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Orientation Materials (for Ford Foundation staff), 1982 (Box 2)
  - Personnel Materials (for Ford Foundation staff), 1981 (Box 2)
  - Policy Change and the Third Sector -- Meeting Materials, Grant Recommendations, Papers, etc., 1980-1983 (Box 2)
  - The Press -- Newspaper Articles, Press Releases, Memoranda Re: Press Conferences and the Press, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Program Officers Manual -- Memoranda, Notes, etc. Re: Procedures, Guidelines, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Program Reviews and Summaries by Program Division and Category, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Program Reviews/Information Papers -- Summaries and Indexes, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Public Policy and Social Organization (PPSO) -- Committee Memoranda, Correspondence, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Publications and Films (Ford Foundation and outside) -- Memoranda, Notes, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Reorganization -- Grant Administration, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Themes (of Ford Foundation programs), 1980 (Box 3)
  - Themes/Program Reviews -- Linn Cary Materials, circa 1981 (Box 3)
  - Themes/Program Reviews -- Linn Cary Materials, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Themes/Program Reviews -- Speeches (given by Franklin Thomas), 1981 (Box 3)
  - Themes/Program Reviews -- Theme Write-ups -- In Draft for September 1981 Board of Trustees Docket (Box 3)
  - Theme Revision Materials (post-Trustee meeting, March 1981), 1981 March (Box 3)
  - Themes and Working Groups -- Outlines, Comments, Budgets, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Thomas, Franklin -- Article, "The Reagan Opportunity in South Africa," Washington Post, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Thomas, Franklin -- Integrating Memo to Board of Trustees (March 1981, outline and drafts) with Background Materials, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Thomas, Franklin -- Integrating Memo/Report to the Trustees Re: Direction and Structure of Ford Foundation Programs, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Thomas, Franklin -- Miscellaneous Correspondence/Letters, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Thomas, Franklin -- Staff Roster, Program Assignments, Notes and Memoranda Re: Integrating Memo to Board of Trustees, Program Review Process, Program Themes, etc., 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Trustees List and Correspondence, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Tuskegee Institute -- Franklin Thomas Speech (draft) and Related Materials, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Tuskegee Institute, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Washington "Urban Imperative for Business" Conference, 1982 (Box 3)
  - "What's Continuing? What's New?" -- Franklin Thomas Memorandum to Trustees, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Writings By/About Franklin Thomas -- "President's Review" from Ford Foundation Annual Reports (1980-1981) and October 1982 Ebony Article Re: Franklin Thomas, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
- Program Reviews, 1979-1984; II
  - National Affairs Program Review, 1979 November (Box 4)
  - International Division Program Review Vol I -- General, Asia and the Pacific (1 of 4), 1979 (Box 4)
  - International Division Program Review Vol I -- Asia and the Pacific and European and International Affairs (2 of 4), 1979 (Box 4)
  - International Division Program Review Vol I -- Latin America and the Caribbean and the Middle East and Africa (3 of 4), 1979 (Box 4)
  - International Division Program Review Vol I -- Population and the Office of the Vice President (4 of 4), 1979 (Box 4)
  - International Division Program Review -- Information Papers (1 of 2), 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - International Division Program Review -- Information Papers (2 of 2), 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - International Division Program Review (1 of 2), 1980 (Box 4)
  - International Division Program Review (2 of 2), 1980 (Box 4)
  - International Division Program Review, 1980-1981 -- Asia and the Pacific (1 of 3) (Box 4)
  - International Division Program Review, 1980-1981 -- Latin America and the Caribbean (2 of 3), 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - International Division Program Review, 1980-1981 -- Middle East and Africa (3 of 3) (Box 4)
  - International Division Program Reviews Background Material (1 of 2), 1981 January (Box 4)
  - International Division Program Reviews Background Material (2 of 2), 1981 January (Box 4)
  - National Affairs Division Program Reviews Background Material, 1981 January (Box 4)
  - Education and Public Policy -- Review of Public Policy and Social Organization Program, 1981 January 19 (Box 4)
  - Education and Public Policy Program Review, 1981 January (Box 4)
  - Education and Public Policy Division Program Reviews Background Material, 1981 January (Box 4)
  - Nutrition and Related Health Program Review (1 of 2), 1981 February 3 (Box 4)
  - Nutrition and Related Health Program Review (2 of 2), 1981 February 3 (Box 4)
  - Nutrition and Related Health Program Review, 1981 February 3 (Box 5)
  - Resources and the Environment Information Paper, 1981 March (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program (DCP) Program Reviews, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program Fiscal Year 1982 Program Reviews, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Program Reviews FY 1982 -- Schedules, Planning Materials, Notes, New Program Division Assignments, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program FY 1983 Program Reviews -- Andean Region and the Southern Cone (1 of 12), 1982 November 29-December 6 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program FY 1983 Program Reviews -- Bangladesh (2 of 12), 1982 November 29-December 6 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program FY 1983 Program Reviews -- Caribbean and Other Latin America (3 of 12), 1982 November 29-December 6 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program FY 1983 Program Reviews -- China and Other Asia (4 of 12), 1982 November 29-December 6 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program FY 1983 Program Reviews -- Eastern and Southern Africa (5 of 12), 1982 November 29-December 6 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program FY 1983 Program Reviews -- India, Nepal, Sri Lanka (6 of 12), 1982 November 29-December 6 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program FY 1983 Program Reviews -- Mexico and Central America (7 of 12), 1982 November 29-December 6 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program FY 1983 Program Reviews -- Middle East and North Africa (8 of 12), 1982 November 29-December 6 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program FY 1983 Program Reviews -- New York: International Affairs (9 of 12), 1982 November 29-December 6 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program FY 1983 Program Reviews -- South Africa, Other Africa and Israel (10 of 12), 1982 November 29-December 6 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program FY 1983 Program Reviews -- Southeast Asia (11 of 12), 1982 November 29-December 6 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program FY 1983 Program Reviews -- West Africa (12 of 12), 1982 November 29-December 6 (Box 5)
  - Developing Countries Program FY 1985 Program Reviews -- Rural Poverty and Resources, 1984 October 10-20 (Box 5)
- Education and Culture Program, 1968-1985; III
  - Regional Files, III.1
    - Africa -- Cultural Preservation and Vitality, 1983 (Box 5)
    - African Theatre -- Memoranda Re: Grant Proposal, Backup, 1981-1983 (Box 5)
    - African Theatre, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
    - Asia -- Cultural Preservation, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Bangladesh -- Dhaka Office Files, Budget Projections, Memoranda Re: Grants, etc., 1982-1984 (Box 5)
    - Bangladesh -- Report, "Programming for Women in the Ford Foundation Bangladesh" by Ruth B. Dixon, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Bangladesh -- RGA's, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Bangladesh -- Sidney Jones Memoranda Re: Greg Pohssel's Trip to Bangladesh, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
    - Bangladesh -- Trip to India and Bangladesh (April-May 1982) -- Planning Materials and Background (Box 5)
    - Bangladesh -- Trip Notes (1 of 2), 1982 (Box 5)
    - Bangladesh - Trip Notes and Background (2 of 2), 1982 (Box 5)
    - Bangladesh -- Trip Report (April-May 1982), 1982-1984 (Box 5)
    - China -- Information Paper, 1983 (Box 5)
    - East Africa -- Background and RGA's, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
    - East Africa -- Nairobi -- Report Re: Kenya Culture, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Eastern and Southern Africa (Nairobi/Botswana) -- Annual Report, Budget Projections, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
    - Eastern and Southern Africa -- Program Management of Region -- Summary of Presentation Given to Board of Trustees at Nairobi Meeting (Sep 29-Oct 1, 1982), 1982 October 6 (Box 5)
    - India -- Correspondence, Memoranda, Meeting Materials Re: Women's Studies and Women's Rights in India, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
    - India -- Folk Performing Arts and Cultural Grants, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
    - India -- Grants Re: Creative Writing, 1979-1982 (Box 6)
    - India -- Grant Proposals and Memoranda Re: Arts and Culture in India, 1981-1983 (Box 6)
    - India -- New Delhi Office Culture Program, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
    - India -- Papanek, Mazumdar Proposal Re: Center for Women's Development Studies, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
    - India -- Report on Visit to India, 1983 (Box 6)
    - India -- Sundar, Pushpa Files -- Ford Foundation New Delhi, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
    - India, Nepal, Sri Lanka -- Budget Projections Fiscal Years 1982-1985 and Grant Summaries, 1981-1983 (Box 6)
    - India, Nepal, Sri Lanka -- Ford Foundation Annual Report, Oct 1981-Sep 1982 (Box 6)
    - Indonesia -- Education/Culture Related Grants, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
    - Indonesia -- Jakarta Office Efforts/Activities, 1984 (Box 6)
    - Latin America and the Caribbean (LAC) -- Andean Region and the Southern Cone (Lima) -- Budget Projections and Robert Myers' Trip Notes, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
    - LAC -- Andean Region and the Southern Cone (Lima) -- Cultural Preservation Grants, 1983 (Box 6)
    - LAC -- Andean Region and the Southern Cone (Lima) -- Cultural Preservation in Peru, 1983 (Box 6)
    - LAC -- Brazil (Rio de Janeiro) -- Budget Projections, Grants Re: Culture, Human Rights, Education and Grant Lists, 1983 (Box 6)
    - LAC -- Brazil -- Rio de Janeiro Office -- Education and Culture Grants Summaries, Rapporteur Notes (DCP Program Review 1982), 1982-1983 (Box 6)
    - LAC -- Caribbean Proposals, 1983-1985 (Box 6)
    - LAC -- Colombia Trip (Jan 1982), 1981-1982 (Box 6)
    - LAC -- Mexico and Central America -- Budget Projections Fiscal Years 1982-1985, 1983 (Box 6)
    - LAC -- Regional -- Grant Proposals and Foundation Programming, Women's Programming, 1981 (Box 6)
    - Middle East and North Africa -- Budget Projection, Grants, etc., 1982-1983 (Box 6)
    - Middle East and North Africa -- Egypt -- Regional Cultures -- Grants Re: Nubian Cultural Center, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
    - Middle East and North Africa -- Palestinian Theatre (El Hakawati), 1983-1984 (Box 6)
    - South Africa -- Memoranda Re: Grant Funding, 1983 (Box 6)
    - South Africa -- Seminar and Reports, 1982 (Box 6)
    - South Africa -- Zulu Oral History Project, 1982-1984 (Box 6)
    - Southeast Asia -- Budget Projections FYs 1982-1985, 1983 (Box 6)
    - Southeast Asia -- Cultural Preservation and Vitality, 1982-1983 (Box 6)
    - Southeast Asia -- Grants Re: Cultural Centers in the Philippines, 1983-1984 (Box 6)
    - Southeast Asia -- Sidney Jones File, 1983-1984 (Box 6)
    - Southeast Asia -- Trip Report by Pushpa Sundar, undated (Box 6)
    - Thailand -- Siam Society Grant Recommendation and Evaluation, 1978-1983 (Box 6)
    - West Africa -- Budget Projections FYs 1982-1985, 1983 (Box 6)
    - West Africa -- Grant for National Museum, Mali, 1983 (Box 6)
    - West Africa -- Museums -- International African Institute (West African Museums Project), 1984 (Box 6)
  - Subject Files, III.2
    - Administrative Questions -- DCP/EC, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    - Alden Seminars/Dorothy Marshall, 1983 (Box 7)
    - American Writers Congress/The Nation Institute (1 of 2), 1981-1982 (Box 7)
    - American Writers Congress/The Nation Institute (2 of 2), 1981-1982 (Box 7)
    - Archaeology (1 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    - Archaeology (2 of 2), 1983-1985 (Box 7)
    - Archaeology and Preservation -- Archaeology Consultants (India), 1983 (Box 7)
    - Archaeology and Preservation -- ICOM/Museum Training Programs for Professionals from Third World Countries, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Archaeology and Preservation -- Sri Lanka Field Archaeology Grant, 1984 January 5 (Box 7)
    - Arts International, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Arts and the Themes (program themes), 1981 (Box 7)
    - Asia Society, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Black Spectrum Theater Company, 1968-1981 (Box 7)
    - Budgets, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Consortium for the Advancement of Private Higher Education (CAPHE), 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    - Child Survival/Fair Start Information Paper, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Christmas File -- Carols in the Garden Materials, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    - Community Colleges, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Corporate Contributions -- Information, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    - Crafts/Employment Generation -- Master Craftsmen's Association of Mithila, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Culture -- Interpretation and Vitality -- Draft of Paper and Related Grant Proposals (1 of 2), 1982 (Box 7)
    - Culture -- Interpretation and Vitality -- Draft of Paper and Related Grant Proposals (2 of 2), 1982 (Box 7)
    - Culture -- Notes, Background Information, Foundation Papers, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Developing Countries Program (DCP) -- Grant Lists -- Activities in Arts and Culture, FYs 1972-1982, 1983 (Box 7)
    - DCP Program Reviews -- Appropriations (1 of 2), 1984 (Box 7)
    - DCP Program Reviews -- Appropriations (2 of 2), 1984 (Box 7)
    - DCP Program Reviews -- DCP Budget Projections -- Education and Culture, 1983 (Box 7)
    - DCP Program Reviews -- DCP Summaries, 1983 (Box 7)
    - DCP Program Reviews -- Education and Culture and Grant Lists, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    - DCP Program Reviews -- Education and Culture Grants Plans (DCP) -- Original, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    - DCP Program Reviews -- Education and Culture -- Notes, Papers, Additional Materials, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    - DCP Program Reviews -- Fiscal Year 1983-1984, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    - DCP Program Reviews -- Rapporteur's Notes from Human Rights Meeting, 1983 (Box 8)
    - DCP Program Reviews -- Reports, Background, Women in the Cities Bibliography, 1981 (Box 8)
    - DCP Publishing Efforts -- Selina Hossain Manuscript and Linn Cary's Revisions, 1983 (Box 8)
    - DCP Women's Program Meeting, 1982 April 27 (Box 8)
    - Documentation Workshop/Festival of India, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
    - Domestic Program Reviews, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Education, 1985 (Box 8)
    - Education -- Report Re: Improving the Transition from Education to Employment by Joy Carol and Related Materials, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Education Program Planning Materials -- Notes, Memoranda, Background, Grant Recommendations, 1980-1981 (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Consultant Report (Kathleen D. McCarthy), "From Cold War to Cultural Development: The International Cultural Activities of the Ford Foundation, 1950-1982" (draft), 1984 October (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- General -- Memoranda, Grant Lists, Budget and Appropriations, Staff Travel Schedule, etc., 1982-1983 (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Grant Lists -- "Grants in Six Southern States, 1970-1984" (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Grant Lists, 1983-1984 (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Information Paper, "Cultural Preservation and Interpretation" Draft Chapter, 1982 November 8 (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Jakarta Meeting (May 13-17, 1985) -- Planning Materials and Previous Cultural Preservation Meeting Materials, 1983-1985 (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Paper, 1982 (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Planning Meeting #1 (Jun 4, 1982) (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Planning Meeting #1 (Jun 4, 1982) -- Major Speaker Points, Notes and Follow-up (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Planning Meeting #2 (Oct 26, 1982) -- Major Speaker Points, Notes (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Program Planning -- Budget Projections (1984-1987) and Program Reviews, 1984-1985 (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Program Planning -- DCP Program Reviews Discussions, Rapporteur's Notes and Follow-ups, Additional EC Materials, 1982-1983 (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Program Planning -- Highlights of Past Quarter Actions, 1983-1984 (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Program Related Investment (PRI) Lists, Summaries, Recommendations (some PRI's from outside EC) (1 of 2), 1977-1983 (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Program Related Investment (PRI) Lists, Summaries, Recommendations (some PRI's from outside EC) (2 of 2), 1973-1983 (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Report, "Major Grants in Higher Education, 1980-1981: An Overview" by Nora Licht, 1982 November 3 (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Staff Meetings -- Memoranda, Reports, etc., 1981-1983 (Box 8)
    - Education and Culture -- Status Reports, Biennial Budget Reports, Appropriations Paper, Note, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Education and Development, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Education Funding -- Other Foundations, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
    - Ethnomusicology -- Asia, Africa and the Middle East, 1983-1984 (Box 9)
    - Evaluations of PUSH for Excellence Project and Programs for Minority Journalists (Ford Foundation funded), 1982 (Box 9)
    - Evaluation Project -- Materials Re: Evaluation of Ford Foundation Programs and Funding, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Field Office Reports and Reports Re: Ford Foundation International Funding and Budgets, 1978-1980 (Box 9)
    - Field Office -- Requests and Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
    - Ford Foundation Grants and Support for Arts, Education, Culture, Women's Programming, etc. (miscellaneous), 1983 (Box 9)
    - Ford Foundation "Letter", 1981 June-1982 April (Box 9)
    - Foundation Grant Letters -- Completed and Blank Forms, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
    - Ford Foundation Support and Interest in Literature and Arts in Asia (incl. short stories by Selina Hossain and others), 1982-1983 (Box 9)
    - Foreign Country Agreements, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Foundation History and Change (1 of 2), 1981-1982 (Box 9)
    - Foundation History and Change (2 of 2), 1981-1982 (Box 9)
    - Giamatti, Buckley and Bernstein, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Hardy, Gladys File, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Historic Sites, 1981-1985 (Box 9)
    - Human Rights, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Human Rights and Social Justice, 1982-1983 (Box 9)